A Glowing Undersea Adventure!
Barbie: The Pearl Princess is a family, animation
film directed by Ezekiel Norton.
Barbie plays Lumina, a mermaid girl with the
power to change the color of pearls.
Cheerful and creative, Lumina finds herself working in a
mermaid salon customizing fabulous hairstyles.
And when Lumina has the chance to attend the royal ball, her
friends adorn her with a gown fit for a princess.
At the ball, villains try to seize power over the kingdom, and Lumina finds within
herself an unexpected power that proves she is much more than a hair stylist.
Lumina (voice), played by Kelly Sheridan.
Kuda (voice), played by Katie Crown.
King Nereus (voice), played by Mark Oliver.
Queen Lorelei (voice), played by Rebecca Shoichet.
Scylla (voice), played by Trish Pattendon.
Caligo (voice), played by John Novak.
Barbie is an American multimedia franchise created by Mattel based on the
eponymous fashion doll created by its co-founder, Ruth Handler.
It began with the release of an eponymous video game in 1984 and has since been featured in more video games, a
film series and in other media formats across technologies like television and the Internet.
It is currently one of the highest-grossing media franchises of all time and has
been referred to among fans as the "Barbie Cinematic Universe".
The film series were released direct-to-video from 2001 and aired regularly on Nickelodeon as
television specials in the United States from 2002, with both running until early 2017.
Since mid-2017, beginning with Barbie Dolphin Magic, Mattel revamped them into streaming television films, branded or marketed them as animated "specials" with a reduced 1-hour video length
as opposed to the feature films beforehand and moved them to streaming media services, predominantly Netflix, but also including Amazon Prime Video, Google Play and Apple TV+.
These films released from late 2017 onwards could still be released on home video formats, although
locally, or get picked up for television broadcast in multiple countries and regions/territories.
Aside from the film series, Barbie has been featured in other media formats, including two animated direct-to-video specials in Barbie and the Rockers: Out of This World and its sequel, Barbie and the Sensations: Rockin' Back to Earth, both in 1987, web series like Barbie:
Life in the Dreamhouse, Barbie: Vlogger, Barbie Dreamtopia, Barbie's Dreamworld and Barbie: Life in the City, television shows like Barbie Dreamhouse Adventures, Barbie: It Takes Two and  Barbie: A Touch of Magic, a live-action film and an interactive short film.
The film explores themes of princess, magic,
mermaid, based on toy, female protagonist.
The tone is lighthearted.